MUHAMMAD RISQI FIRDAUS

Software Engineer

Bandung, Indonesia | +6282245200501 | Email: risqifirdaus@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mrfirdauss/ | github.com/mrfirdauss-20

SUMMARY

An undergraduate informatic student who has a devotion and experience in digitalization, especially in web and chatbot development. He is keen to learn about building and developing technological things. Specialized in web development using various stacks (PHP, Node js, Golang, Python) he is able to quickly learn and acclimate to new technologies. Besides that, he has a lot of experience being a leader in teams and national organizations.

WORK EXPERIENCES

PT Paragon Technology and Innovation – Jakarta, Indonesia

Backend Engineer Intern (April 2022- Present)

- Building an API for a warehouse management system using PostgreSQL and express js.
- Responsible for implementing the whole user management API.

Hikeryco – Bandung, Indonesia

Chief Technology Officer (July 2021 - Now)

- Developing websites using PHP and MySQL for web services.
- Deploying the web via IDCloudhost VM platform and maintaining DNS for www.hikery.co.

GhazLabs Indonesia – Bandung, Indonesia

Software Engineer Intern (April 2022- May 2022)

- Developed web app using Golang and various memory such as Redis, MySQL, and elasticsearch.
- Experienced in building Golang architecture using hex architecture and implemented docker-compose.

Skillup – Bandung, Indonesia

Vice Manager of Technology (September 2021 - April 2022)

 Responsible for developing and coordinating a team consisting of 4 people on web development and also with other departments.

Schoolpad.id - Bandung, Indonesia

Quality Assurance (September 2020 - December 2020)

- Checked and tested the quality of try-out questions that will be served to more than 10.000 users.
- Check any bugs on the website, and try out the system, and user experience.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Himpunan Mahasiswa Informatika – Institut Teknologi Bandung

Vice Head of Aspiration Commission of DPP (June 2022- Present)

- Responsible for gathering aspirations among 800 students of Informatics and Information System majors.
- Responsible for delivering and supervising the implementation of aspirations.

Panitia Persiapan Program Ramadhan dan IdulAdha - YPM Salman ITB

Head of Sponsorship (April 2022- Present)

- Responsible for building partnerships with companies, more than 14 companies, and for gathering funding and other support for P3RI's event.
- Led and coordinated a team consisting of 9 undergraduate students from 5 top universities.

Salman Spiritual Camp – BMKA Masjid Salman ITB

Steering Committee (November 2021- Present)

- Responsible for developing and designing BMKA Masjid Salman ITB's first phase regeneration project, Salman Spiritual Camp.
- Supervising the continuity and accountability of the regeneration event on a national scale.
- Serving impact for more than 1750 participants and 500 committees for three seasons.

Gamatra Pulang Kampung – Paguyuban Mahasiswa ITB Blitar Raya

Head Committee (November 2021- Present)

- Responsible for leading the team to expose gamatra on an offline fair at 6 high schools at Blitar Raya.
- Expose ITB in front of more than 6000 high school students.

EDUCATION

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG (2020 - Present)

B.Eng, Informatic Engineering - GPA 3.16/4.0 for 74 credits

PROJECTS

DNA and Disease WebApp

Backend Developer (May 2021)

DNA and Disease WebApp is a web that is able to compare the DNA of patients and disease DNA using Boyer Moore and KMP Algorithm, filter the input, determine the distance of the DNA and save the data of DNA and search history in MySQL. This web application was built using MySQL, expressjs and React. Responsible for developing the server application and building the Levenshtein distance algorithm.

Website Image Compressor

Backend Developer (May 2021)

The web application is built using Python Flask. This application is able to compress an input image using the SVD image matrix algorithm. Responsible for developing the web server request and sent services.

Water Potability Analysis

Data Analyst (Maret 2021)

The data on water potability was analyzed using python and google collab. The data were examined using hypothesis testing and exploratory data analysis. Responsible for analyzing the data hypothesis and drawing the data visualization.

Wecome - KM ITB x Ditmawa ITB

Fullstack Developer (September 2021 - Maret 2022)

Welcome is a website that provides competition information for ITB students. Built the first version website using PHP MySQL. Was responsible for building the backend system and deploying the first version.

Konsul.in

Backend Developer (January 2021)

Konsulin is a consultation web that was built for muslimhackfest 2021. Was responsible for leading the development team. Develop Whatsapp chatbot and website services using node js. Maintaining the JQuery for the websites. Deploying the web via Heroku (bit.ly/Konsulln).

ADDITIONAL

Technical skills: Python (Matplotlib, Pandas, Seaborn, Sklearn), MySQL, NodeJs, PHP, Problem Solving, Web Development, Excel (<u>Linkedin Certification</u>), Redis, Golang, Elasticsearch, Docker, CSS (<u>Linkedin Certification</u>), Sequelize, Blogging.

Language: English, Arabic

Awards: Semifinalist of Muslim HackFest 2021, Semifinalist HackGov UGM 2021, Awardee Beasiswa Pembinaan Rumah Kepemimpinan